Guide to the International Postcard Collection, ca. 1900-1982 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
International Postcard collection ca. 1900-1982 and undated
Yoder, J. Russell
19.00 linear feet Extent: circa 24,500 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00615
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The International Postcard Collection was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library from J. Russell Yoder as a gift in 1996 and 2000.
Biographical Note
Mr. Yoder is a postcard collector and Duke University alumnus (class of 1938).
Collection Overview
International collection of picture postcards (6500 items, ca. 1900-1982), almost all of which date from 1920 or earlier. Arranged by country and filed in 28 albums. Almost all European countries are represented, and there are many rare postcards from Russia. (96-0135) (7 lf)
The addition to this collection (18000 items, from ca. 1900-1950) also is international in scope, but focuses on the United States. The collection comprises fifty, three-ring binders that hold picture postcards in pocketed mylar sleeves. About two-thirds of the cards show scenes in the United States, including all 50 states, the District of Columbia, and Puerto Rico; state capitols; worlds fairs; and other tourist destinations. Thirteen of the fifty binders document Atlantic City, N.J., and are subdivided by the images shown, including boardwalks, beaches, and hotels. The rest of the collection comprises postcards from other countries, including Austria, France, Germany, Italy, Spain, and the Netherlands. Asia, Africa, Latin America, and North America are also represented. A small group of postcards depicts costumes from around the world. (00-422) (12 lf)
Subject Headings
Postcards -- History; Postcards -- Europe; Postcards -- United States; Postcards -- Russia (Federation); Postcards -- Collectors and collecting; Postcards -- Washington (D.C.); Postcards -- Puerto Rico; Postcards -- New Jersey -- Atlantic City; Postcards -- Africa; Postcards -- North America; Postcards -- Central America; Capitols; Ethnic costume; Russia (Federation) -- Pictorial works; Europe -- Pictorial works; United States -- Pictorial works; Atlantic City (N.J.) -- Pictorial works; Washington (D.C.) -- Pictorial works; Puerto Rico -- Pictorial works; Africa -- Pictorial works; North America -- Pictorial works; Central America -- Pictorial works; Postcards; Postcard albums
Contents of Collection
- Accession 96-0135
  - Africa I and II (Box 1)
  - Africa III and Andorra, Liechtenstein, Malta, Monte Carlo, San Marino, Vatican, Gibraltar, Fiume (Box 2)
  - South-East Asia and Asia (Box 3)
  - Austria, Hungary and Balkan (Box 4)
  - Benelux and Caribbean (Box 5)
  - Central American and China, Japan (Box 6)
  - Northern Europe and Central Europe (Box 7)
  - France and Germany (Box 8)
  - Great Britain and Italy I (Box 9)
  - Italy II and London, Paris (Box 10)
  - Near East and North America (Box 11)
  - Pacific and Scandinavia (Box 12)
  - Schweiz (Switzerland) and South America (Box 13)
  - South America II and Spain, Portugal (Box 14)
- Accession 2000-0422
  - United States, AL-CO (Box 1)
  - United States, CT-IA (Box 1)
  - United States, KS-MA (Box 2)
  - United States, MI-NH (Box 2)
  - United States, NJ-OH (Box 3)
  - United States, OK-VA; includes Puerto Rico (Box 3)
  - United States, VT-WY, DC (Box 4)
  - United States, 1900-1906,UND/BK, AL-CT (Box 4)
  - United States, 1900-1906,UND/BK, DE-KY (Box 5)
  - United States, 1900-1906,UND/BK, LA-MT (Box 5)
  - United States, 1900-1906,UND/BK, NE-ND (Box 6)
  - United States, 1900-1906,UND/BK, OH-UT (Box 6)
  - United States, 1900-1906,UND/BK, UT-WY, DC (Box 7)
  - New York, UND/BK, 1900-1906 (Box 7)
  - Asia, UND/BK; includes Near East, 1900-1906 (Box 8)
  - Africa, UND/BK, 1900-1906 (Box 8)
  - New York City (Box 9)
  - New York City, UND/BK (Box 9)
  - New York (Box 10)
  - Costumes (Box 10)
  - Expo [Various World Fairs] (Box 11)
  - North America, UND/BK; includes Central America, 1900-1906 (Box 12)
  - Europe 1, UND/BK, 1900-1906, B-F (Box 12)
  - Europe 2, G-M (Box 13)
  - Europe 3, UND/BK, 1900-1906,N-S (Box 13)
  - Europe 4, UND/BK, 1900-1906,S-Y (Box 14)
  - Europe, UND/BK, 1900-1906,Austria (Box 14)
  - Europe, UND/BK, 1900-1906,France (Box 15)
  - Europe, UND/BK, 1900-1906,Germany 1, A-F (Box 15)
  - Europe, UND/BK, 1900-1906,Germany 2 (Box 16)
  - Europe, UND/BK, 1900-1906,Germany 3 (Box 16)
  - Europe, UND/BK, 1900-1906,Italy 1 (Box 17)
  - Europe, UND/BK, 1900-1906,Italy 2 (Box 17)
  - Europe, UND/BK, 1900-1906,Spain (Box 18)
  - Europe, UND/BK, 1900-1906,Netherlands (Box 18)
  - Atlantic City, 1, Greetings (Box 19)
  - Atlantic City, 2, Boardwalk (Box 19)
  - Atlantic City, 3, Beach (Box 19)
  - Atlantic City, 4, Streets-Restaurants (Box 19)
  - Atlantic City, 5, Piers (Box 20)
  - Atlantic City, 6, Hotels (Box 20)
  - Atlantic City, 7, Hotels (Box 20)
  - Atlantic City, 8, Hotels (Box 20)
  - Atlantic City, 9, Hotels (Box 21)
  - Atlantic City, 9a, Elephant-Sand Artists-Night Scenes-Inlet (Box 21)
  - Atlantic City, 10, Buildings, Misc. (Box 21)
  - Atlantic City, 11, Modern A.C. (Box 21)
  - Atlantic City, 12, Booklets (Box 22)
  - Capitols, DC (Box 22)
  - Capitols, AL-MD (Box 22)
  - Capitols, MA-OR (Box 22)
  - Capitols, PA-WY (Box 23)
  - Atlantic City, UND/BK (Box 23)
  - South America, UND/BK; includes Caribbean 1900-1906 (Box 24)